<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Andrew Braithwaite | The Land of Shattered Dreams]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/blog/categories/andrew-braithwaite/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-24T13:59:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Braithwaite]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Birthday to me]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/blog/2011/04/25/happy-birthday-to-me/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T10:00:13+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/blog/2011/04/25/happy-birthday-to-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So another year gone and I have reached the ripe old age of 36. I guess I will have to accept that I am now middle aged. The chances of me playing centre-half for City or becoming a rock god are probably now on the remote side, so what I am going to do for the second half of my life?</p>

<p>The first half has been pretty eventful. I’ve been married for the best part of 14 years to the girl I met at university, and despite what I may say, I don’t regret any of it.</p>

<p>I have two lovely boys who drive me insane but who I wouldn’t be without.</p>

<p>I’ve been pretty successful at work, despite some interesting career choices. I’ve even ended up managing a team of 30, which I am sure will amuse a number of my former colleagues. I’ve worked in Belgium for a year, worked for the UK’s biggest bank, the largest IT company in the world and even the Guernsey Government. I’ve worked with some brilliant people and written some pretty code.</p>

<p>It’s not all been fun. Number 1 son was born four 3 months early, weighing 1lb 9oz. I wouldn’t want to repeat the night he was born, stressful doesn’t begin to cover it. I can only guess how much the NHS spent looking after him, but I am eternally grateful to everybody who did. I find it amazing that he shows absolutely no signs of what he want through.</p>

<p>So the last 35 years have been pretty good on the whole. What to do now?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
