<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: welcome | The Land of Shattered Dreams]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/blog/categories/welcome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T10:44:41+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Braithwaite]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the Land of Shattered Dreams]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/blog/2013/04/28/welcome/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-28T20:33:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.landofshattereddreams.com/blog/2013/04/28/welcome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been blogging at as <a href="http://typingincolor.com">typingincolor</a> for about three years. It started as
an exercise to learn a bit about wordpress, and was a place where I reviewed 
whatever DVDs and books I’d been looking at. </p>

<p>As time progressed, I began to add some stuff about work and technology. 
In particular I talked a bit about the journey the company I was working for
was taking into the world of agile development. I also put in some stuff about
technology that I was currently looking at.</p>

<p>It worked (and works) pretty well, but I’ve decided to try something new. I’ve
chosen to use <a href="http://octopress.org">octopress</a> as it will let me use some technologies I’m 
interested in. I particularly like that the styling is done using <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">sass</a> and
the content written in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">markdown</a>. That fact that it’s built on ruby is a 
happy coincidence.</p>

<p>The other thing I do really like is that it uses <a href="http://git-scm.com/">git</a> to publish the content. 
I can run a local copy of any changes I make and preview them locally, I can then
push the content up to <a href="https://www.heroku.com/">heroku</a> where they are visible to the world.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
